A more common means of high-speed Internet connection for both residential and business customers is Digital Subscriber Link, or DSL.
With DSL, a customer has a dedicated phone line from the origin to a telco office. The closer a customer is to the office, the faster the connection.
For this reason, many people cannot get DSL because they are not close enough to a telco office. There are two types of DSL connections you need to know about for the exam.
SDSL, or Synchronous DSL, in this form of DSL, upload and download speeds are the same. This is often used in businesses that need fast uploads.
This is far more expensive than ADSL, Asynchronous DSL. Speaking of ADSL, ADSL is the most common form of DSL used in homes and businesses.
ADSL has different upload and download speeds, with download speeds being much higher than upload speeds.
Another common means of high-speed connection for a residence or business is that of a cable modem.
Besides the obvious difference of using a cable TV provider for an Internet connection rather than a phone company for DSL, there is one other major difference.
Cable Internet tends to run over shared bandwidth, meaning that customers in a concentrated area are sharing the same bandwidth pipeline.
As a result, speeds tend to be slower during peak usage hours, which for many is early- to mid-evening. That said, cable modem speeds tend to be faster overall than for that of DSL.
The most important takeaway for the exam is that DSL connections are on dedicated lines and cable modem connections are typically not.